So many people are going through challenging times right now and it's really crucial that we develop the human skillset that enables us to be present with another person.
So firstly, what we always want to do is acknowledge their feelings.
Simply feeling seen, de-escalates the intensity of the situation.
Number two is reassure the person that their feelings are valid.
A lot of times we get hung up on this, we think that by saying to someone,
your feelings are valid, that we are agreeing with everything that they are saying.
But no, we are just saying your experience is this and your feelings are valid and I see that.
And number three is to help them feel valued.
When we do this, when we offer someone presence, whether we are a leader or a manager, a colleague or a parent,
when we offer presence, we help the person feel grounded in the situation and to develop a sense of wholeness and agency as they move forward.